AKSHATH SIVAPRASAD

SUMMARY

I am self-driven, dedicated, a team player, and a quick learner. I am willing to learn anything to get the job done. I like to code for fun; I've participated in several hackathons and competitions such as USACO (gold medalist) and worked on various personal projects. I like to spend my free time rock climbing and singing.

CONTACT

■ akshath@berkeley.edu

4 (425) 633-9271

in /in/akshathsivaprasad

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley Electrical Engineering & Computer Science 2018

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Java, C#, Python, C, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Scheme **SELECTED COURSES:**

Data Structures, Machine Structures, Database Systems, Efficient Algorithms, Data Science, Computer Security, Artificial Intelligence, Operating Systems, Networking, Web Design

EMPLOYMENT

Apptio

Software Development Intern

May 2015 to Sep 2016

I worked on two main projects over two summers. The first was a complete revamp of the healthcheck system, transitioning from Pingdom to an internal logging utility backed by Splunk. The second involved developing new features for AdHoc Query, an on-the-fly chart/table manipulation tool. Mostly backend, but required some UI/translator works as well. Required knowledge: Java, JavaCC, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, XML.

Science Infinity

Founder

Aug 2011 to Current

I am the founder of Science Infinity, a nonprofit organization aimed towards broadening the academic horizons of elementary and middle school students. Science Infinity has experienced explosive growth, comprising of hundreds of students in 5 states. Members consistently win at national-level competitions. I coordinated weekly meetings, managed a large volunteer pool, and helped host state-level chapters of competitions such as You Be The Chemist! and North South Foundation.

BSD Capital Construction Management

Management Intern

Oct 2013 to Apr 2014

I was mentored by several architects and engineers (electrical, structural, mechanical, etc.) in project management and other concepts. I also participated in design, permitting, and bidding processes for Odle Middle School.

MetaCAPTCHA

Software Security Intern

May 2013 to Sep 2013

MetaCAPTCHA is an anti-spam service designed to protect web applications by employing metamorphism borne from the use of both CAPTCHAs and proof-of-work puzzles. I primarily worked on integration tools as well as a solution to replay attacks. I presented my work at the 2013 ASE Symposium. Required knowledge: PHP, JavaScript, Linux-based systems.

PROJECTS

Gitlet

A basic version of a popular version control system, Git, implemented from scratch in Java. Employs SHA-256 hashing and GZip compression, and includes features such as merge, interactive rebase, remote push/pull etc.

WordamentPlayer

I used Java and JNA to write WordamentPlayer, a bot designed to play Wordament, an online Boggle-like game in which players compete to find the most words in a 4x4 board.

Toggle

Toggle is a combination between the games Tetris and Boggle. Required knowledge: JavaScript, HTML, CSS.